JAMES EDWARD TOMASSONI

Software Engineer

301-943-7914 jtomassoni@gmail.com Denver, CO/Remote qithub.com/jtomassoni www.jamesetomassoni.com linkedin.com/in/jtomassoni

Summary

Software engineer that strives to solve complex problems in an effort to make all easier to understand. As a highly motivated individual that believes two core components of innovation are challenging the status quo and collaboration, I bring high levels of energy and critical analysis to any team, so that we can create quality deliverables for stakeholders while simultaneously sharing team knowledge.

Skills

React.js, Express.js, Node.js, Python, Django.js, Djoser, Mongoose, MongoDb, Atlas, Heroku, RESTful API, CSS, HTML, Git,

Projects

921steak \\ Demo site with full admin CRUD, used to sell other small biz on responsive upgrades \\ http://921steak.com

- Designed Full-Stack SPA in three developer team using Django, Djoser, Python, React, and Styled Components.
- Fully responsive, includes authenticated functionality for CMS, allowing full crud of menu items to logged in users.

Botanical Babbles \\ Social media style app for the plant community \\ https://bbfe.herokuapp.com/

- Created Full-Stack SPA in five developer team using Express.js. Node.js, MongoDB, React.js.
- Acted as Scrum Master to ensure direction, focus and equal contribution.
- Established workflows, daily stand-ups, pair programming sets, and code reviews.

JTX \\ Web app for navigating past and upcoming spaceX launch details \\ http://jtx.herokuapp.com

- Built Front-End SPA using JavaScript, React.js, CSS and React Bootstrap.
- Implemented RESTful API for fetch calls to SpaceX launch data.
- Delivered smooth, feature rich and user friendly experience by employing responsive design elements.
- Improved user experience by linking third-party video player plug-ins, giving the app more engagement value.

Tower of Hanoi \\ Logical brain teaser, math based video game \\ https://jtomassoni.github.io

- Developed a game using JavaScript logic to ensure a seamless and engaging user experience.
- Utilized DOM Manipulation with CSS structure to create dynamic and easy to understand game.

Experience

TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT // 2013-present

Earth, Wood and Fire // Remote Consulting

- Designed proprietary digital signage solution for multi-location restaurant; sales +16%.
- Revamped website in collaboration with original web designer; user traffic +5%; online ordering implemented.
- Implemented a social media management plan; average digital response time decreased from 72 hrs to 12 hrs.
- Maintained 15 Office PCs + GSuite accounts for ownership and management.

ENTERPRISE PRODUCT SPECIALIST // 2018-2020

FareHarbor // Denver, CO

- Spearheaded company wide bookability project, managing 75 global and multilingual employees, created est \$70M in 2020 Revenue resulting in promotion to Enterprise Product Specialist.
- Promoted to Senior Product Specialist by reaching 150% productivity goals in first year.

CUSTOMER SERVICE TEAM LEAD // 2016-2018

OpenTable // Denver, CO

- Managed team of 14 agents, coaching and motivating on technical and soft skills with tracked KPIs.
- Promoted to Team Lead through consistently exceeding expectations as an agent.

Education

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING IMMERSIVE | General Assembly, Remote BACHELOR OF ARTS: Criminology | Towson University, Baltimore, MD